time hi I'm John Faulkner welcome to the
intermediate lesson on how to build
single bass drum speed
LFS and the beginner lesson these
exercises can be applied
I with both feet 10 so it's if your Dell
based on player
you still need to practice the
techniques to control the speed
with you right and your left foot if
you're single best umpire
is exercise we perfect fit K so in these
examples were gonna be focusing more on
developing a quick double and then the
second exercise due notice for
redeveloping
quick triple and says a couple different
techniques you can use to do this
on the first to do a quick double as
using the Kyoto texting
now we have a video on from us is dot
com teaches that case of you wanna go
ahead
and learn how to develop a quick double
you can do that
just one wing that's fine too that's how
I did it when I first started I just
tried by Kurt Hummel and then the
technique I am involved itself
I'm the other techniques you can use is
the slide technique
K Dave Atkinson has I'm video on dramas
and a common teachers
slight K as let's just jump into the
first exercise
and you know this is a groove I wouldn't
necessarily recommend playing for a
whole song
or something like that so if you are
working on this exercise don't go your
band and start playing at the whole song
but it's something you could use as a as
a little Phil
or something like that but it is just an
exercise in so I just encourage you to
this music
we are passing by itself but don't
necessarily
play for five minutes straight with the
fact that probably won't go over well
that said let's jump into the exercise
I'm
it just gonna be to 16th notes on da
on and a beach P case 01 and that too
and out three and %uh for and i won
and died too and 3 and ask for k andreas
ca start this release of her show have
sounds
someone to show you guys how it sounded
play you know I 280 be thrilled to see
you can you know kinda see the end goal
or what you
you know what you can easily get 2k I
know you guys can easily do that
it's all about starting at the slow
temple and then working without
I also known as their when I was playing
the exercise at a beach minute I wasn't
really using any specific technique
other than
simply just heal up and plan the two
strokes
K a lot of the techniques like the slide
Hill told they kinda have
a speed threshold where I'm you won't
necessarily use them
at at temples like a TV three-minute or
100 beats per minute session playing 60
pounds but your you know
with field so you kinda jump into it
around 110 and that's where it's
starts to be very very comfortable and
the timing of it works out perfectly for
me
but before that are usually just play to
crypto strokes
out the next one is one actually gonna a
lot of questions about and that is
how do I quick triple struck and
there is basically to deploy singer one
is just using
your toe just play 3 quick notes
warning at to be can 3 an forty at
K and this exercise has been developed
to work on that case but like I said no
other one is it that says something a
play its role song
but you're gonna need to be able to do
three base from strokes in a row
so I thought why don't we work on it
here K that so that the first one is as
quick
coaster the second anything to it is
using kinda I shields' whole
hybrid thing I call it which which job
is basically
you know you hit one stroke when you
drop your foot
and then you hit two more on the way up
K something to show you guys this
exactly how it looks
and others will show you the full can
see 6s helps
OKC guys gonna
to figure out what works good for you
you know no one
really when I was starting I know we
didn't have this kind of technology were
i can
I had a teacher that was dismissed
hotline I'm
so I had known the show with me really
other than my private teacher who
we've there's no way to know if he
actually knows are not and I didn't know
necessary to ask for
I'm so it's all about you know work
figure out what works best for you and
kinda involving that technique
you know there's so many different
genres and every single driver has
little variations that are different in
the techniques that they use
so I'm says hi recommend just a watch
other drivers
what are they doing to do a picture of a
stroke and figure out what works best
for you
and then definitely practice at uses
exercise because
you need to develop some speed some
control to do a quick triple
with the single pedal test let's do the
exercise the first wanna do it seventy
beats per minute d
so the quick triple as something I'm
definitely working on and I'm actually
going between 2n
but he'll told variation and then just
80 variation and just try to stay out
you know what's the most consistent
sometimes I find I do
the hotel a variation of it I get a
strong first row
a week middle and a strong and stroke so
like I said before is all about their
works best for you and practice practice
practice
practice that said let something that's
one
this morass is going to start moving
around the drums and I absolutely love
playing
this hasher size and it's a great one
too number one
practice your single bass drum pedal
speed and them into
practice working on the drums and the
way ever written is just too unless
they're
to Anaheim Tom to on the men Tom to in
the low Tom
out with the double in between each one
does but eventually
you can get a point where you just
playing around whatever
K so that sent let's jump in this on at
her beats per minute
this
the
the alright guys remember it's not
race case not about beatings the last
person to the next hour
the scene is faster it's not about that
it's just about to volcanic
control I'm said about the speed that
you need to play the style of music
you're actually want to play okay and
suggests
work on what you need to do I'm for the
band or the music you're playing with a
highly recommend you do that and
are seeing guys in the advanced video
we're going to talk about some
different concepts to develop single
based on speed
a senior this
tight
the